A Finding Aid to the LeRoy Neiman Papers, 1938-2005, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
television - 2.1: 1970, 1978, 4.1: 1972, 1974, 1975, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1985, 1994, 1995, 3.1: Call of the Wild 1993, see also ABC, CBS, American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, The Lone Ranger
ABC Sports - 2.2: ABC Sports
Ampex Video Art - 3.1: Superbowl XII, 1978, 4.1: 1980
Arlene Herson Show - 4.1: 1989
The Black Stallion television show - 2.1: 1990
CBS Sports - 2.2: CBS Sports, 3.1: Superbowl XII, 1978
Channel 13 - 2.1: 1976
Cityscope - 4.1: 1989
Dinah! (Dinah Shore) - 3.1: Dinah! (Dinah Shore television show) 1974-1977
KCTA -TV St. Paul - 2.1: 1976
Larry King - see King, Larry
Kup's Show (Irv Kupcinet) - 4.1: 1972, 1982
Merv Griffin Show - 2.1: 1976, 1983, 4.1: 1980, 1989
NBC - 3.1: Sculpture 1977-87, 3.1: NBC Peacock Project 1997
"The New Odd Couple," ABC TV - 2.1: 1982
Regis and Kathie Lee - 4.1: 1988, 1996
Shukan T.V. Guide, Japan - 2.1: 1996, 3.1: 1984 Olympics, Los Angeles
TV Food Network - 2.1: 1993
TV Gallery with Ron Parris - 2.1: 1979, 4.1: 1979
T.V. Guide - 2.1: 1975
T.V. Guide Japan - 2.1: 1996, 4.1: 1984
TV Shopper - 2.1: 1979, 4.1: 1973, 1980
Tele Planning International, Tokyo - 2.2: Tele Planning International, Tokyo 1993-98
Today Show - 3.1: WNBC Traffic Helicopter 1981-93
WGBH TV Boston - 2.1: Charities 1994, Charities 1996
Wonderama TV Show - 4.1: undated 1970s
The Year of the Runner TV series, LeRoy Neiman host - 4.1: 1979
Tenenbaum, Judy and Harold - 2.1: 1984, 1986, 1988, 2.2: Harold and Judy Tenenbaum
Tennessee - 3.1: Women's Basketball Hall of Fame, 1993, 3.1: Iroquois Steeplechase, Nashville, TN, 1993, 3.1: Blues Ball 1997 -2004, see also Gregory, Jack; Morris, Gary and Elizabeth; Murphy, Libby; Perkins, Carl; Rudy, Jeanette Cantrell; Tigrett, John and Pat Kerr
tennis - 3.1: Nelson Mandela Tribute 1997, 3.2. Winners, 1983, Harry N. Abrams, 4.1: 1975, 1980, 1985, 1988-89, 1997, 1999
Adoption Guild Annual Tennis Tournament, Tennis Country - 3.1: Adoption Guild Tennis Tournament 1980
Alan King Caesar's Palace Tennis Classic - 3.1: Alan King Caesar's Palace Tennis Classic 1980-83
American Airlines Tennis Games - 2.1: 1976
Ashe, Arthur, Arthur Ashe, 1980 - 2.1: 1980, 4.1: 1980, 1984
Association of Tennis Professionals - 4.1: 1984
The Ball is in Your Court - 4.1: 1979
Blanchard, Mike - 4.1: 1975
Blood Tennis, 1980 serigraph - 4.1: 1980
Borg, Bjorn - 4.1: 1977, Bjorn Borg - 3.1: Sweden Exhibitions 1976-77, 4.1: 1980
Casals, Rosey - 4.1: 1975
Center Court, Madison Square Garden - 4.1: 1986
Conner, Bart - see gymnastics
Connors, Jimmy - 4.1: 1977, 1988, 1994
Court, Margaret - 4.1: 1975
Doubles - 4.1: 1973, 1977
Emerson, Roy - 4.1: 1998, see Laver, Rod
Evert, Chris - 4.1: 1976, 1994 and ov, see Appendix A
Back Hand - Chris Evert - 4.1: undated, 1981 ov
Chris, 1973 drawing - 3.1: Hammer Galleries Solo Exhibition 1975-76
Forest Hills - 3.1: RFK Tennis Tournament 1972-1979, 4.2: Playboy 1960, see Appendix E
Get Shot - 4.1: undated
Gonzales, Richard (Pancho) - 4.1: 1972, 1975, 1977, Pancho Gonzales, 1970 - 4.1: 1970, 1972
I Love New York Pro Celebrity Tennis Tournament - 2.1: Charities 1982, 4.1: 1982
Intelligent Doubles, by Skip Singleton - 3.1: Skip Singleton Tennis Books 1988-89
Intelligent Tennis by Skip Singleton - 3.1: Skip Singleton Tennis Books 1988-89
International Tennis Hall of Fame - 3.1: International Tennis Hall of Fame Group Exhibitions 1977-78
Kennedy, Robert F. - see Robert F. Kennedy Pro Celebrity Tennis Tournament
King, Billie Jean - 4.1: 1973 ov
Laver, Rod
Rod Laver at Wimbledon, 1970 drawing - 3.1: Rotonda Superstars 1973-75
Rod Laver, 1980 watercolor - 4.1: 1996
Rod Laver and Roy Emerson, 1980 watercolor - 3.1: Adoption Guild Tennis Tournament 1980, 4.1: 1998
Lendl, Ivan - 4.1: 1989
McEnroe, John - 4.1: 1983, 1989, 1994
Men's Doubles - 4.1: 1977
Mixed Doubles - 3.1: Skip Singleton Tennis Books 1988-89, 4.1: 1978, 1981
Mulloy, Gardner - 4.1: 1977
Net Shot, undated - 4.1: undated
Noah, Yannick - 4.1: 1997
Palm Beach Tennis Masters - 4.1: 1973 ov
Racketeers, 1975 silkscreen - 4.1: 1975
Riggs, Bobby - 4.1: 1973 ov
Robert F. Kennedy Pro Celebrity Tennis Tournament - 3.1: Robert F. Kennedy Pro Celebrity Tennis Tournament 1972-79
Roche, Tony - 4.1: 1973 ov
Rosewall, Ken - 4.1: 1975
Sabatini, Gabriela - 4.1: 1996, 1997
Smash - Stan Smith - 4.1: undated
Stadium Tennis, 1981 - 3.1: Stadium Tennis Billboard, 1981
Tennis - Sudden Death, 1973 - 4.1: 1998
Tennis Magazine - 4.1: 1973, 1975
Tennis Masters (McEnroe and Lendl) - 4.1: 2000
Tennis Players, serigraph - 3.1: Circle Gallery 1972, 3.1: RFK Tennis Tournament 1972-1979
Turnberry Isle Racquet Club - 3.1: Turnberry Isle Yacht and Racquet Club Exhibitions 1982-83
Volvo Masters serigraph, 1983 - 3.1: Volvo Masters Painting 1983, VC: 1983
Washington, Malivai - 4.1: 1997
wheelchair tennis - 2.1: 1980
The Wimbledon Restaurant - see restaurants and bars
Texas Is... - 4.1: 1986
textbook (usage of art in) - 2.1: 1998, 2000, 2002, 4.1: undated, undated 1990s, 1992, 1996
theater - 3.1: Borstal Boy 1970, 3.1: "Busker Alley," 1995, 4.1: 1964, 1969, 1981, 1991, 1999, see also musicals
Inherit the Wind - 4.1: 1956 ov
Theater Collection of the Museum of the City of New York - 4.1: 1983
theft - 2.1: 1980, 3.1: Dyansen Gallery Playboy Collection touring exhibition 1989-90, 4.1: 1973, 1981, 1986, 1987, 1990, see also forgery and vandalism
Thomas, Duane - 3.1: Gridiron Football News 1971-73
Thompson, Bobby - see The Shot Heard 'Round the World, 1991
Thornton, Tony - 4.1: 1995
Thornton, Wayne - see boxing
The Three Tenors - see opera
The Thrill of Victory, by Bert Sugar - 2.1: 1977, 4.1: 1978
Thurmond, Strom - 2.1: 1984, 3.1: Miss U.S.A. Pageant 1978
TIME Magazine - 3.1: TIME Magazine Cover Portraits Exhibition, National Portrait Gallery and Minnesota Museum of Art 1969
Times Square, 2001 - 4.1: 2003
Tiger Tops Pvt. Ltd. - 2.1: 1982
Tigrett, John and Pat Kerr - 2.1: 1992, 1993, 1999, 3.1: Blues Ball 1997-2004
Time Out New York Magazine - 4.1: 2000
Timothy Yarger Fine Art - see exhibitions
Timoney, John - 4.1: 1996
To, Bobbie - 4.1: 1984
Toney, James - 4.1: 1994
Top Secret! 1984 film - 4.1: 1984
Topps - see trading cards
Torre, Joe - 3.2. Casey at the Bat, 2000, 4.1: 2002
Torres, Jose - 4.1: 1966
Tour Eiffel, 1993 - 4.1: 1995
Tour de Trump - 3.1: Tour de Trump
Tour de Trump, 1989 - 3.1: Tour de Trump
The Toy Store - see exhibitions
track and field - see also running, 4.1: 1982, 1987, V: Jesse Owens International Trophy Awards 1983-2000s
Dekker, Mary - V: 1980s
Drake Relays - 3.1: Drake Relays 1979
Jenner, Bruce - 2.1 1977, 3.1: Winter Olympics, Lake Placid 1980, 4.1: 1987
Joyner-Kersee, Jackie - 4.1: 1999, V:1990s, Jackie Joyner-Kersee, 1993 - 3.1: Millrose Games 1986-1995
Lewis, Carl - 3.1: Victor Awards 1981-1985
Millrose Games - 3.1: Millrose Games 1986-95
Muhammad Ali Invitational - 4.1: 1977
Off and Running, 1978 - 4.1: undated 1980s
Owens, Jesse - 3.1: Drake Relays 1979, 4.1: 1990, 1998, 2000
Jesse Owens, 1983 - 4.1: 1983, 1984, 1986, 2000
Jesse Owens Foundation - 2.2: Jesse Owens Foundation Board of Directors 1990-2000
Jesse Owens International Trophy Awards - 4.1: 1983, 1984, 1986, 1987, 1989, 1992, 2000, V: 1990s
Jesse Owens Track Classic - 4.1: 1990
U.S. Olympic Track and Field Trials - 4.1: 1980
trading cards
Kayo - 3.1: Kayo Joe Louis Boxing Card 1991
Topps - 2.1: 1992, 3.1: Topps Celebrity Trading Cards 1992
Upper Deck - 2.1: 1992
travel agency - 4.1: undated
Tretyakov Museum, Moscow - see exhibitions
Trinidad, Felix - see boxing
Tropicana Resort & Casino - see casinos
Trottier, Bryan - 4.1: 1976
Truax - 3.1: Gridiron Football News 1971-73
Trump, Donald - 1.1: New York Friars Club c., 3.1: Tyson vs. Spinks 1988, 3.1: Tour de Trump 1989, 4.1: 1987
Donald Trump, 1986 - 2.2: Trump 1987-96
Trump Plaza - 2.2: Trump 1987-96, 3.1: Tyson vs. Spinks 1988, 3.2. LeRoy Neiman: An American in Paris, 1994, Correspondence, 4.1: 1996
Harrah's Trump Plaza, Atlantic City - 3.1: Harrah's Trump Plaza Opening, Atlantic City 1984
Baccarat at Harrah's - 3.1: Saks Fifth Avenue Catalog 1994-1999, 4.1: 1984
Harrah's Polo - 2.1: 1988, 4.1: 1988
Trump Polo Club - 4.1: 1985
Trump Taj Mahal, Atlantic City - 2.2: Trump 1987-96
Trump, Ivana - 2.2: Trump
A Tribute to the Movies, 1989 - 3.1: Houston Film Fest
Tulane University - 4.1: 1974
Tunnel Club, New York - 3.1: Baird Jones' Group Exhibitions, New York 1988-89, 4.1: 1988
Turkey - 2.1: 1975
Turnberry Isle Yacht and Racquet Clubs - 3.1: Turnberry Isle Yacht and Racquet Club, Exhibitions 1982-83
Turner, Tina - 4.1: 1981
Twentieth Century Fox Film Corportation - 2.1: 1976
'21' Club - see restaurants
Two Bar Men, 1965 - see bars
Tyson, Mike - see boxing
U
UCLA LeRoy Neiman Center for the Study of American Society and Culture - 3.1: UCLA, 1998-present
U.S. Army - 1.1: Military Service, see also Army vs. Navy
U.S. Postal Service - 3.1: U.S. Postal Service Superbowl Stamps 1988, 3.1 ov.
U.S. Savings Bonds - 3.1: U.S. Savings Bonds Campaign 1987-88
Edwin A. Ulrich Museum of Art, Wichita State University - 2.1: 1981
The Ultimate Seduction, by Charlotte Chandler - see Chandler, Charlotte
Ultraviolet - see Dufresne, Isabelle
unicorn - see animals: unicorn
Unitas, Johnny - 3.1: Gridiron Football News 1971-73
Johnny Unitas, 1970 drawing - 3.1: Rotonda Superstars 1973-75
Johnny Unitas, 1997 - 3.1: Wheaties 1997
United Airlines - 4.1: 1983
United Cerebral Palsy Association - 4.1: 1988, 1992
United Nations, U.N. Postal Administration - 3.1: United Nations Stamps 1988-96
United States Sports Academy - 2.1: 1989
United Way - 3.1: The Shot Heard 'Round the World, 1991
Universal Geneve Timepieces - 3.1: Universal Geneve Watch Promotion 1995-96
University of California at Los Angeles - see UCLA
University of Chicago - 1.1: Education and Teaching, Miscellaneous, undated
University of Denver - 2.1: 1979
University of Oklahoma - 2.1: 1982
University of San Francisco - 4.1: 1988
University of Southern California - 3.1: Los Angeles Olympics 1984
University of Texas at Austin - 4.1: 1994
Upstairs Gallery - 2.2: Upstairs Gallery 1980-89, 4.1: 1973, 1985, 1989, see also exhibitions
V
Vail, CO - see skiing
Van Der Marck Editions - 3.2. Monte Carlo Chase, 1988, Van Der Marck Editions, Ltd.
vandalism - 4.1: 1978, see also theft, forgery
Vanity Fair Magazine - 4.1: 1996
Varga, Alberto - see Playboy Magazine
Vargas, Fernando - see boxing
Variety Clubs International Distinguished Artist Award - 1.1: Awards
Varipapa, Andy - see bowling
Venice, Italy - 2.2: Helmut Drinhaus 1988-2000
Ventura, Jesse - see wrestling
Vernon, Jackie - 3.1: Economic Opportunity Atlanta 1968 ov.
Versace, Gianni - 4.1: 2001
Via Video - 2.1: 1983
Viagem E Tourismo Magazine - 3.1: Brooklyn Bridge, 1995
Victor Awards - 3.1: Victor Awards 1981-1985, 4.1: 2003
Video Magazine - 2.1: undated
Vienna, Austria - 2.1: 1996
Village Nursing Home - 4.1: 1982
W
WNBC - see helicopter
Wajima - 3.1: Hawaii and Japan 1974
Walker, Doug - 3.1: Soft Paintings 1989
Wall Street Journal - 4.1: 1969 ov
Walsh, Coach Bill, Bill Walsh, 1993 - 3.1: Bill Walsh, 1993, 4.1: 1993
Ward, Laura - 4.1: 2004, see also Merce Cunningham Studio under "dance"
Warhol, Andy - 3.1: Neiman/Warhol 1981, 3.1: "Art", Group Exhibition at Area, 1985, 3.1: Baird Jones' Group Exhibitions, New York 1988-89, 4.1: undated 1980s, 1986, 1987, 1988
Warwick Hotel - see Players Hotel
Washington, Malivai - see tennis
watch - see Classic Moments Watches or Universal Geneve Timepieces
Watergate hearings - 2.1: 1973
Waterhouse, Alma Jones - 2.2: Alma Jones Waterhouse 1977-80, 4.1: 1979
Wayne, George - 4.1: 1996
Webb, Eugene 'Fat Daddy' - 3.1: Economic Opportunity Atlanta 1968 ov.
Webster, Jack - 2.1: 1990, 1992, 1994, 1995
Weeb - see Ewbank, Weeb
Weiner, Claire - 2.1: 1970s, 1987
Weisberg, Tim - 2.1: 1977
Welles, Orson - 4.1: 1989
Welzer, Irv - 1.1: Friars, 2.1: 1977
Wenzel, Lee - 2.1: 1985
West Side Story - see musicals
Westbury Hotel - 2.1: 1978
Westheimer, Dr. Ruth - 4.1: 1999
Wheaties - 3.1: Wheaties 1997
Whitaker, Pernell "Sweet Pea" - see boxing
White House - 2.1: 1978, 1980, 3.1: Newport Jazz Festival 1975-2004, 4.1: 1978, Easter at the White House - 4.1: 1988
Whitney Museum of American Art, Whitney Biennial - 4.1: 1985, 1989
Who's Who - see Marquis Who's Who
Whores, Wars & Tin Pan Alley - 4.1: 1969
The Wildcats, 1978 - 3.1: The Wildcats, 1978 file
wildlife - see animals, LeRoy Neiman On Safari
The Wildlife Experience - 3.1: "LeRoy Neiman on Safari," The Wildlife Experience, Parker, CO, 2003
Williams, Bernie, Bernie Williams, 2003 - 3.1: Bernie Williams, 2003
Williams, Cleveland - see boxing
Williams, Ted - see also television: WGBH
The Splendid Splinter - 3.1: Williams at Bat, 1980-1991, 4.1: 1993, 2002
Williams at Bat, 1980 painting and 1991 serigraph - 3.1: Williams at Bat, 1980-1991, 4.1: 1981, 1991, 2002
Win a Few, Lose a Few, 1972 boxing documentary film - 4.1: 1972
Windsor Gallery - 4.1: undated 1970s
wine - 4.1: 1997, see also champagne
labels - 3.1: David Frost Wines 2001, 4.1: 1992, 1996, see also golf: Atlanta National Golf Club California Merlot
Wine Country Film Festival - 3.1: Wine Country Film Festival 1990
Wine, Women, and Cigar, 1996 - see cigars
Winged Foot - see golf
Wingmead - 2.2: JoAnn Perse Gallery 1983-02
Winners, 1983 - 2.2: ABC Correspondence, 2.2: Neiman-Marcus 1983-88, 2.2: Sterling/Winters Company 1983-84, 3.1: Hanson Galleries New Orleans and Carmel, 1983-84, 3.2. Winners, 1983, Harry N. Abrams, 4.2: The Ring Magazine
Wisconsin - 2.2: Bobby Hinds 1990-2000
Wittnauer International - see Universal Geneve
Wolf, Martin B. - 4.1: 1964
Wolfberg, Lee - 4.1: undated 1980s
Wolfson, Mr. and Mrs. Robert L. - 4.1: 1967, 1980
Women of Excellence - 2.1: 1985
Women's Basketball Hall of Fame - 3.1: Women's Basketball Hall of Fame, 1993
Women's Sports Foundation - 2.1: 1983
Wood, Jan - 2.1: 1991, 1997, 1998
Wooden, John, Coach John Wooden, 1975 - 2.1: 1975, 1985, 4.1: 2001
Woods, Tiger - see golf
Word, Rob - 4.1: 1977
World Biographical Hall of Fame - 2.1: 1991
World War II - 1.1: Military Service, 4.1: 1998
world wide web - 3.1: LeRoy Neiman Website 1997-present
wrestling - 4.1: 1973, 1992, 1999
Baumgartner, Bruce - 2.1: 2001, 4.1: 1999
Schultz, Dave, Dave Schultz, 1996 - 3.1: Dave Schultz 1996
Ventura, Jesse - 3.1: Jesse Ventura 1999
Wyeth, Andrew - 4.1: 1987
Wyland - 4.1: 1993
X
Y
YMCA - 4.1: 1992
Yale University - 4.2: Playboy Parodies - Harvard and Yale
Yarger, Timothy - see exhibitions: Timothy Yarger Fine Art, also Bowles Galleries
The Yearling, by Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings - 4.1: 1994
Yellin, Lou - 2.1: 1991, 1992, 1998
Young, Trip - 4.1: 1970
Youngman, Henny - 1.1: Friars, 2.1: undated, 1987
Henny Youngman, 1987 - 4.1: 1987
Yugoslavia - 4.2: Playboy 1969, see Appendix
Z
Zabrin, Michael - see Michael Zabrin Fine Art
Zaire - 4.1: 1974, 2000, 2002
Zelaya, Jose - 2.1: 1972, 1973, 1976, 1977
Zeran, Ken - 2.1: 1990, 1991, 3.1: '21' Club, 1990 (photo)
Ziegenfuss Gallery, Sarasota, FL - 4.1: undated 1990s
zoo - 3.2. LeRoy Neiman On Safari, 1996, Zoo Tour correspondence
Olympics in art; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Sports artists; Art -- Study and teaching; Printmakers -- New York (State) -- New York; CBS Sports; Playboy Enterprises; Super Bowl; ABC Sports; Ali, Muhammad, 1942-
- Biographical Material, 1938-2004, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-3, 77; 3.3 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains information pertaining to Neiman's family, military service, education and teaching experience, and the major galleries and publishers that have represented him. The series also includes artist biographies, awards and distinctions and membership information.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  1.1: General Biographical Material, 1938-2004, undated
  1.2: Representing Galleries and Publishers, circa 1970s-2003, undated
  1.3: Major Studies and Publications on LeRoy Neiman, 1990
  - General Biographical Material, 1938-2004, undated; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains information and paraphernalia regarding the artist's family, childhood, military, education and memberships, as well as artist biographies, awards, certificates, and identification. All correspondence from family members is included in this series. Files are arranged alphabetically by topic and then chronologically.
    - Artist Biographies, circa 1975-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Awards, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - American Academy of Achievement Golden Plate Award, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - B'nai B'rith Bill Corum Awards "Sportsman of the Year" Award, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Boxing Writers Association Marvin Kohn "Good Guy Award,", 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Lonsdale International Sporting Club Honoree, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - American Sportscasters Association Humanitarian Award, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Ellis Island Medal of Honor, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Inductions, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Citations and Miscellaneous Prizes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Honorary Degrees and Academic Honors, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - Art Institute of Boston, Honorary Diploma, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Franklin Pierce College, Honorary Doctorate, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - St. John's University, Honorary Doctorate, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - St. John's University, Gold Medal of Honor, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Iona College, Honorary Doctorate, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Hofstra University, Honorary Doctorate, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - St. Francis University, Honorary Doctorate, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - St. Bonaventure University, Honorary Doctorate, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Collectors, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Teaching, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - Art Institute of Chicago, 1945-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Art Institute of Chicago, 1972-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous Institutions, 1954-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Family, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - Lydia Hoelscher, Earl Neiman, and Ollie Serline, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Materials Related to Janet Byrne Neiman, 1965-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - People Related to Lynn Quayle, Assistant, 1983-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Military Service, WWII, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Materials, 1945-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Issues of Company 3703's Monthly Magazine, Baptism Blade, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - The New York Friars Club, 1977-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The New York Friars Club, 1987-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The New York Friars Club, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Residence - Hotel des Artistes, 1 West 67th Street, New York, NY, 1986-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Who's Who, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
      - Marquis correspondence, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Marquis correspondence, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Marquis certificates, 1987-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous VIP Biographical Directories, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Writings and Notes, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Oversized materials relating to biographical subjects, Archival Resource Key (Box 77)
  - Representing Galleries and Publishers, circa 1970s-2003, undated; 1.2; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains information on the primary galleries and publishers representing Neiman throughout his career. Biographical information concerning Hammer Galleries and Knoedler & Co. includes information and articles about the Hammer family and Maury Leibowitz, the proprietors of Knoedler & Co. For more information on the artist's primary representing galleries and publishers, please see Appendix B, which gives a detailed history of these matters. Please note that files on specific exhibitions at these galleries are filed among the chronological project files of Series 3.1 and the dated files of Series 4.1 and are listed in the Index under "exhibitions".
    - Felicie, Inc., Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
      - Advertising, circa 1973-circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - FKH Editions, Inc. and Hammer Galleries, 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Lawsuit Against Felicie, Inc., Correspondence and Legal Documents, 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lawsuit Against Felicie, Inc., Correspondence and Legal Documents, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hammer Galleries and Knoedler & Co., Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
      - Biographical Information, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Advertising, Hammer Galleries Ads (not specifically serigraph related), 1963-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Advertising, Serigraph Release Ads, 1975-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Advertising, Serigraph Release Ads, 1975-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Advertising, Serigraph Release Ads, 1975-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Advertising, Serigraph Release Ads in Art Magazines, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Advertising, Serigraph Catalogs and Ad Fliers, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Appraisal Documents and Price lists, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Contracts and Receipts, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and Lists, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Press, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bowles Galleries, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
      - Auction Catalogs, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1997-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Major Studies and Publications on LeRoy Neiman, 1990; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    - A Sociological Study of the Artist LeRoy Neiman, and 1000 Neiman Collectors by David Halle and Louis Mirrer, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, circa 1940s-2004, undated; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 3-19; 16 linear ft.)
  This series contains personal and business correspondence, as well as collections of cards and literature on other artists, notes and jottings by Neiman and artwork by children.
  Series 2 is arranged into 4 subseries:
  2.1: Dated Correspondence, circa 1960s-2004
  2.2: Correspondence Collections, 1974-2002, undated
  2.3: Other Artist Letters and Literature, circa 1970s-1977, undated
  2.4: Office Records, 1968-2004, undated
  - Dated Correspondence, circa 1940s-2004; 2.1; Archival Resource Key